

SUMMARY

Dedicated and efficient Full-stack Engineer with 2 years of industrial experience in MERN stack. I've always found coding intuitive and have pushed myself to learn the most effective ways to achieve a result. I can adapt to any technology rapidly making myself flexible upon any tech stack and can quickly integrate into a team, so I can provide value to the company and the customers.

CONTACT INFO

MOBILE: 0774 229 289

EMAIL: sandeepa8956@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT END:

React, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Ant Design, Material UI, Bootstrap, Auth0, Google Maps API

BACK END:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, REST API

DATABASES:

MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase

ADDITIONAL LANGUAGES:

Java, C#, C++, C, Python

VCS:

GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket

IDEs and TOOLS:

JEST, ESLint, Prettier, Swagger, Postman, Adobe XD, Figma, Jira, VSCode, Intellij IDEA, Eclipse EE

KAVINDU S. LIYANAGE

www.kavindus.com, github.com/KavinduLiyanage

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer - CabbageApps Jan 2022 to Present

FusionX – An Exponential Cloud Financial Suite

- ✓ Developing the Frontend using React-TypeScript.
- ✓ Doing code review, merge, and deploy process.
- ✓ Involving debugging and bug fixing to solve production issues.
- ✓ Writing readable, reusable, scalable, and maintainable code to achieve efficient and productive development.

Associate Full Stack Engineer - Orel IT May 2021 to Dec 2021

Workwise – Online Marketplace for Financial Properties

- ✓ Worked as a Frontend team leader with 4 team members.
- ✓ Designed, and developed the Frontend using React-TypeScript.
- ✓ Developed the Backend using Node, Express, and MongoDB.
- ✓ Worked with Google APIs to integrate Google map functions.

Software Engineering Intern - Orel IT Nov 2020 to Apr 2021

Homaze – Online Quotation Generating Web app for Contractors

- ✓ Developed the Frontend using React-JavaScript.
- ✓ Developed the Backend using NodeJS-Express.
- ✓ Worked with Git/GitLab for version control.

EDUCATION

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT)

BSc (Hons) in Information Technology Specializing in Software Engineering - Nov 2017 to Dec 2021

Rahula College Matara

GCE Advanced Level - 2017 (Index No. 5976278)

✓ ICT - C

✓ Combined Math - S

✓ Physics - S

GCE Ordinary Level – 2014 (Index No. 41751850)

✓ 7 - "A" passes, 1 - "B" pass, 1 - "C" pass.

PROJECTS

FusionX – Core Banking System

Description:

FusionX is a core-banking platform developed to help standardize and optimize the operations of the branches.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Development of Breadcrumb navigation, OD Appraisal creation, Guarantor Details Management, Income & Expenses Analysis, Loan Calculation, Lead Creation, and Current Account Management. Involved in the process of bug fixing and hotfixes.

Technologies:

React-TypeScript, Redux-toolkit, Ant-Design, Tailwind CSS, AuthO, Redux-Thunk, SASS, Styled-components, Recharts

WEBSITES AND SOCIAL LINKS

GITHUB:

github.com/KavinduLiyanage

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/kavinduliyanage

PORTFOLIO:

www.kavindus.com

MEDIUM:

medium.com/@KavinduLiyanage

BLOG:

<u>kavinduliyanage.wixsite.com/techpurs</u> <u>ue</u>

PERSONAL INFO

FULL NAME:

Kavindu Sandeepa Liyanage

NIC: 981682629V

DOB: 16th June 1998

GENDER: Male

MARITAL STATUS: Single

CURRENT ADDRESS:

No. 88/A/1, Koswetiyana Rd, Brahmanagama, Pannipitiya.

PERMANENT ADDRESS:

'Sandeepa', Hediwatta, Waralla, Matara.

REFEREES

Mr. Chamith K. Ranaweera

Tech Lead

CabbageApps (Pvt) Ltd

Email: chamith@cabbageapps.com

Mobile: +94 77 352 3896

Mr. Adeesha Savinda de Silva

Senior Solutions Engineer WSO2 Lanka (Pvt) Ltd

Email: adeesha@wso2.com

Mobile: +94 76 354 0500

Workwise Web App with Admin Panel

Description:

Workwise is an online marketplace that connects people who want to rent out their properties, office listing with people who are looking for properties in that locale. For owners and affiliates participating in Workwise is a way to earn income from their property.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Development of property searching function using map, Google map viewing function, property adding function, multiple images uploading function, property contract signing function, reserved properties viewing function, analytics functions of admin panel and property management functions of admin panel.

Technologies:

React-TypeScript, Redux, Redux-saga, Google API, Material UI, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS EC2, S3, Formik

Homaze Online Quotation Generating App

Description:

Homaze helps remodelers & renovation experts create estimates in minutes on-site, turn those estimates into professional-grade proposals, and share them with their clients. Remodelers can manage all client communication in one place.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Development of Customers Management, Account Management (Contact and Professional Info), Images upload with gallery view, Property details functions, Scope of Work section, Quotation customizes, finalize and share functions (Download, Print)

Technologies:

ReactJS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Material-UI, SASS, ChartJS, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS EC2, S3, Formik

• Online Fashion Store App (Personal)

Description:

Web Application for Online Fashion Store. MERN Stack E-commerce web application.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Add Products with Details(Images). Retrieve all Products Details in Card view with Image Slider. Edit, Update and Delete Products. Manage Discounts. Main Search in Navigation panel. Quick Search. Filter by price range, branch availability, and categories. All images related works.

Technologies:

ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB Atlas, Heroku, GitHub Source Code:

https://github.com/KavinduLiyanage/Fashion-Store

Portfolio Web App (Personal)

Description:

My personal portfolio website to showcase my work, projects, skills, social links, and about myself.

Technologies:

ReactJS, Material-UI, GitHub, Vercel

Source Code:

https://github.com/KavinduLiyanage/kavindu-portfolio

Deployment:

https://www.kavindus.com